Guide to the Meyer Lissner Papers, 1903-1923 (inclusive), 1910-1920 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
- Series 11. File Cards
  - Letters,[UNK] (Box 68)
Lissner Correspondence for February-December 1909. The special folders in the Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League Correspondence 1907-1909 contain letters of the following terminal dates: Dickson (Feb. 6, 1909), Heney (March 10, 1909), Rowell (Dec. 4, 1908), Weinstock (Feb. 17, 1908). This fact suggests that somewhere should be a file of Lissner correspondence for 1909, apparently after the Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League had wound up its work. Unless Lissner went away during this period, one should not expect the Lissner files to be broken here.
Lissner Correspondence for 1914. This, however, is probably all here contained within the Californi Outlook file, since Lissner took over the management apparently. I mention this as a lack merely for appearance sake since Lissner files run from 1910-1921 as such.
Lissner Correspondence 1921-1930. This is the U. S. Shipping Board period (1921-1925) till death. Where is this correspondence? Surely he did not refrain from all correspondence, although in Washington and later inactive politically.
Of course, it cannot be said now, after so brief an examination, that every letter is present when the folders appear to be intact in their contents. When one considers the vagaries of filing clerks, the handing over of a letter to X for his perusal, and the requests for a return of certain documents to the writer, one can expect certain gaps. After an examination of the reference materials in the Lissner Papers, it became evident that a great many letters are to be found scattered through all the subject-indexed folders of these materials. This fact will have to be considered when indexing the letters.
It may also be observed that certain letters were reproduced for political purposes, or certain others were open letters, both kinds present at times in considerable numbers in various forms (printed, mimeographed letters; cards; pamphlets, leaflets). This type of literature was widely reproduced in newspapers. It may be assumed, therefore, that here, at least, is one connection between the Newspaper Clippings and the Lissner Correspondence, although this direct tie is less important than the relationship between the Correspondence and the Reference Materials.
The examiner does not presume to offer any suggestions in respect to the ultimate form of filing and indexing----except to express the pious hope that the intention be kept in mind to take this great opportunity which the ordering of the Lissner Papers presents to lay a firm foundation for a definitive system which shall hold good for all the other political materials yet to be collected. Already, in the Lissner Papers, is to be seen a direct connection with the Irish and work Papers (correspondence and speeches of these gentlemen) now in the Borel Collection. If further papers are added it is of paramount importance that the same methods of cataloguing be followed. To this end the examiner will make one suggestion after all: let a dictionary catalog be now begun of the persons and organizations (publications, associations, organized political groups) involved in the Lissner Correspondence, based for the time being simply upon the information in the papers. Each correspondent ought to be listed (after his signature or letterhead), with his official status. Each organization ought to be listed by full title and appropriate cross-references if necessary, its card bearing the principal officers and backers as listed on its stationary (the ones involved in correspondence could be marked with see-reference). Each publication should be indexedunder its name and location, its editor and publisher listed, togetherwith such other information as Ayer's Guide for the period might furnish which would be useful, and with such other employees as are involvedin the correspondence. This index would be the means of locating correspondence and identifying political figures. Political office-holders may also be so identifiedif indexed under their positions. The file should embrace all the materials in the Borel Collection which are related, and should be both brief and accurate, more detailed information being sought in the index to each group of papers or in the papers themselves. Fiat Index!
REFERENCE MATERIALS
The same sort of examination was made of these materials. Here, however, the examiner removed a considerable portion of their contents to the shelves. The materials removed were books and pamphlets, alphabetically filed on the shelves, and in nearly every case of removal a slip was put into the folder listing the pamphlet briefly by author and title. By such means a great deal of room was found, so that all the Lissner Reference materials now are contained in the two four-drawer cabinets. A good deal of cleaning was necessary. Much overlapping was eliminated, but very likely some other method of arrangement may be felt desirable. As stated above, there is considerable correspondence in these files. Likewise, there are many newspaper clippings. All three principal types of materials are thus interconnected. Many folders contain but one clipping, a card, or a photograph; others are exceedingly bulky. It is probalbe that these materials formed sortof morgue for the California Outlook. The pamphlets are arranged alphabetically by author (or title if no author), but should be catalogued with reference to Library of Congress entries or indentifications. It may be well also to check these pamphlets with the Stanford University Library and the Union Listof Serials.
In this connection, it may be remarked that if the Lissner Papers and their present and future neighbor papers are to be housed and used as a small reference library for specific purposes, that a file of the California Outlook ought to be placed in the room, along with the California Weekly and the Pacific Outlook. Copies of the California Blue Book for these years would also be very useful.
There are many articles cut, torn or clipped from papers and periodicals among these reference materials. They should be properly bound in folders. It would also be wiseto bind manuscript speeches.
NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS
Allen's Bureau furnished Lissner for many years with hundreds of clippings relating to him and various topics and persons in whom he was interested. These clippings are filedin folders arranged chronologically and now contained in four wood-and-fiber boxes and a fiber transfer case. There was no time to examine them beyond identifying the contents sufficiently for labeling.
Scores of newspaper clippings are contained in the Reference Materials and the Correspondence, both from Allen's and from personal snipping and tearing. The examiner will leave the problem of what to do about this to his successors.
One suggestion may be made: it would be wise (perhaps) to mount the clippings on sheets of regular paper (mimeograph paper would do). This would form a better-looking file, easier to handle, making possible the proper use and preservation of the clippings. At present they are bunched and even wadded together; irregular clippings are in constant danger of being torn or mangled. Long and wide clippings (or pages) stick out of folders only to be frayed and torn. The folders are hard to handle since they are designed for flat contents, but great wads of small narrow clippings in the bottom of each folder distort its shape, take up too much room in the drawer and make spilling too likely. Imagine filing sausages in correspondence folders! After mounting it would be farless easy to lose a small clipping in the shuffle, while the paper could be marked for filing under subject if necessary.
Clippings and tear-sheets from other sources than Allen's should also be trimmed and mounted. At present they are scattered through the Correspondence and Reference Materials.
Harry N.M. Winton
August 13, 1936
Additional Notes: Lissner Collection
Johnson Letters:
Calender cards have been made for the Hiram Johnson correspondence in possession of the family of Meyer Lissner in Los Angeles. The cards are marked with a double red pencil line across the upper right hand corner, diagonally. If the letters are ever acquired, there will be no need to make new cards. A sample card with the red lines and explanation thereof appears at the first of each `year' of cards.
Roosevelt Letters:
Copies of Roosevelt letters are found in Shelf B, Case III, though the cards are filed in the regular card index.
There are no rods in the last four cases of Lissner calendar cards and care should be taken in handling to prevent the cards from being spilled. Additionl 3 ¥ 5 files which are purchased should be, prefereably new, equipped with rods.
Correspondents listed Alphabetically
- AB - AL
  - Abbott, James W. - L.A. mining engr. 1915City Club politics
  - Abrams, Hatty H. - S.F. jewelry rep. 1908, 11City Club politics
  - Abrahamson, Hugo - L.A. 1911real est.
  - Academy of Political Science - N.Y. 1912s. Henry Raymond Mussey Sec.
  - Addams, Franklin P. - S.F. Mar. 9,?a New Yorker pers.
  - Adams, J. Q. - N.Y. 1908asst. sec. Ant Commission of The City of New York - re: City Club
  - Adams, James H. - L.A. 1911public util, etc.
  - Adams, Sane - Chicago 1914Hall House to Rowell re Heney typed copy not signed
  - Adler, Dr. & Bertha - S.F. 1921congrats Shipping Bd. apptmt
  - Advertising Club of L.A. 1915s. J.F. Wadley, sec, s. Clifford A. Williams (Member's Tick)
  - Aeronautical Society of Calif, L. A. s. A. H. Rose, sec., Earle Remington;? Water
  - Aetna Life Ins. Co. - Hartford, Conn. 1907s. Morgan G. Bulkeley, pres. loan
  - Alameda Co-Clerk - Oakland 1912John P. Cook, clk., s A.E. Johnstone, chf dep. clk
  - Alaska Pacific Steamship Co. L.A. 1910s. E.J. Edwards, genl agt - H.F. Alexander, pr
  - Aldao, Campos & Del Valle - Buenos Aires, Argentina 1920Wall Sf. N.Y. office
  - Alderson, Harry E. - S.F. M.D. 1916re: Commonwealth Club & pers.
  - Alexander, George - L.A. 1911mayer.
  - Alexander, H.F. - Tacoma, Wn. 1921tel. pres. Alaska Pacific S.S.Co. pers., (1)
  - Alexander, J. - Saeramente Nov. 9, 10,?tel.
  - Alexander, J. L. B. - Phoenix, Asiz. 1912tel
  - Alexander, Jewel - S.F. Lawyer 1919pers., (1)
  - Alexandria, Hotel - L.A. 1912, 13,?s. U.F. Newlin, rm clk; s. Joseph Reichl, asst mgr
  - Allen, Carroll L.A. Lawyer 1915, 17bus. polit?
  - Allen, Crombie - Ontame Cal. ed. The Daily Record - Calif. Assb. 1912, 17
  - Allen, Edward O. - S.F. 1916, 18,?19
  - Allen, Robert S. Para. 1918
  - Allen, W.S. L.A. 1912
  - Allen, William H. - N.Y. 1907, 11, 12Bureau of Municipal Research Sec. & dit.
  - Allison, Ralph T. - Chicago 1919pers. indus examno Illinois State Indus. Cmmn.
  - Altland Fruit Co. - L.A. 1907bus.
- AM - AR
  - Amador Co. Republican Central Com. - Sutter Creek ,1912C.E. Richards sec.
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science - Philadelphia 1911s. N. J. Smith - Fisher s. Carl Kelsey, sec., s. L.S. Rowe, pres.
  - American Assoc. For Labor Legislation - N.Y. 1912, 15, 16, 17s. John B. Andrews, sec., Irving Fisker, pres.
  - American City - N.Y. 1911Arthur H. Grant, pres. & ed., American City Publishing Co
  - American City Bureau - N.Y. 1914s. Ralph G. Stoddarel see., dept. of exhibits
  - American Civic Assoc. Washington, D.C. 1911, 16, 18s. * Richard B. Watrous, sec.
  - American Defense Soc., Inc. N.Y. 1915s. J.F. Hubbard, charmn com. on org.
  - American Express Co. Paris 1913
  - American Guaranty and Trust Co. - Wilmington, Del. 1921s. J.M. Frere, pres.
  - American Jewish Relief Com. - L.A. 1920s. * W.L. Newton, campaign dit.
  - American Independence League - L.A. 1919s. * Frank S. Hutton
  - American Institute of Current History - Berkeley 1915
  - American Magazine - N.Y. 1912s.?
  - American Ribbon - Carbon Co - L.A. 1917s. W. E. Sibertsen per M.E. Graham pres.
  - American Steamship & Custom House Brokers, Inc. - L.A. 1916s. Charles S. Brown, pres.
  - American Window Cleaning Co. - L.A. 1917s. L. Joseph, mgr.
  - Amerige, E.R. - Fullerton, Cal. 1912res. agt Girard Fire & Marine Ins. Co.
  - Anderson, George B. - Sacramento, 1909, 11, 12 -Direct Legis League, Peoples Legis B, sec. L.A. Good Govt. Org., Progressive Publicity Bureau
  - Anderson, James A. - L.A. lawyer 1910, 1911, 13, 15, 18
  - Anderson, John N - Calif. Senator Santa Ana 1915, 16Norwalk State Hospital Bd.
  - Andreani, F.M. - Wn., DC 1919, 1920
  - Angeles Mesa Land Co L.A. 1916s. Fred W. Forrester, sec. & gen. mgr.
  - Angellotti, F.M. - chief justice Supr. Ct. Calif. S.F. 1918, copy not signed
  - Annis, Sylvia M. - S.F. 1908
  - Arbitration, Lake Mohonk (N.Y.) Conf. on Internat'l - Mohonk Lake, N.Y. 1911H.C. Phillip see.
  - Arlett, Arthur - S.F. building construction 1912, 13, 15, 16, 17,Panama - Pal. Internat'l Expos. Cmmn.
  - Arlett, Catherine M. - S.F. 1918Mrs. Arthur
  - Armer, Evelyn D. - S.F. 1911
  - Armstrong, Abel - L.A. 1912
  - Armstrong, E.H. - Grass Valley, Cal. 1911princ. C V. Bus College
  - Arndt, M.S. - Stockton 1912tel? same as below or father of
  - Arndt, Stanley M. - Stockton lawyer 1921
  - Arney, C.E. - Spokane, Wash. 1912western immigr. & indus agt. Northern Pal. Ry. Co
  - Arnold, Bion J. - L.A. 1911offices in Chicago & N.Y.
  - Arnold, G.S. - S.F. 1911tel.
  - Aronson, S. - L.A. 1916vp Aronson - Gale Co
  - Aronson-Gale Co L.A. 1916s. Geo. Newbergh
  - Arper George W. - Oakland 1911
  - Arroyo Seco Chamber of Commerce - L.A. 1911s. H.M. Chapman, pres.
- AS - AV
  - Associated Advertising Clubs of the World. N.Y. 1917s. Lewellyn B. Pratt Nat'l Program Com.
  - Associated Charities - L.A. 1906s. T.J. Stuart, see.
  - Associated Charities L.A. 1911st Spencer K. Sewell, see.
  - Associated Oil Company - S.F. 1920s. F.B. Henderson chairman finance com.
  - Association for Betterment of Public Service - L.A. 1919s. A.C. Denman, Jr. asst. to
  - Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Ry Co. (Coast Luices). L.A. 1907, 11, 12, 15, 18s. W.H. Brewer gen. mgr st. John S. Bytne L.A. asst. Poss. Traffic mgr. M.W. Reed, asst. atty
  - Auditorium Hotel - Chicago, Ill. 1912s. J.J. Calvey asst. mgr. F.B. Tyson comptroller
  - Augastine, S.M. - San Rafael, Cal. 1912
  - Austin, Lloyo B. - Pasadena 1912, 13prep. Camp Losadena at Switzer's Falls & see L.A. Y.M.C.A.
  - Automobile Acceptance Corp. - L.A. 1921s. Eugene F. Kline v.p. s. M. Pickarts mgr. inter-U.S. exch
  - Automobile Club of So Calif. - L.A. 1911, 12, 17 &st. S.C. Geary, sec.; Guy Van Alstyne Ralph Reynolds, mgr. ius. dept.
  - Avery, Robert C. - Redlands, Cal. 1908
  - Avey, John L. - Redlands physician 1910, 11, 12, 13Calif. Senate Calif. Assb.
  - Avey, W. A. - Riverside, Cal. 1912, 15pres. Roosevelt Repub. Club of Riverside Co.
  - Avery, Russ - L.A. 1908, 10, 11, 12, 13, 16, 17Repub. Cent. Com. of L.A. Co. chairman, lawyer
  - Alexander, F. B. - Wn. D.C. 1913see. to u.s. Rep. Wm. Kent
  - American Assoc. for Internat'l Conciliation - N.Y. 1911, 13s. Frederick P. Keppel, sec.
  - American Red Cross - Seattle, Wn 1918s. E.J. Saunders, com. on personnel, (1)
  - Annals - Philadelphia 1912mag. of Am. Acad. of Polit. & Soc. Science s. Clyde S. King assoc. editor
  - Anonymous - L.A. 1911re: Women's sufferage s. Veritas Vincit
  - Bacley, H. K. - L.A. 1920sec. to Dan Murphy
  - Babcock, Kendric C. - Tucson, Ariz. 1908pres. U. of Ariz.
  - Bade, W. F. - Berkeley 1913pres. Calif. Assoc. Sec. Conserv. Wild Life
  - Baer, John Willis - L.A. 1911, 12, 13, 15, 16, 17, 18pres. Ocadental College
  - Bailey, Arthur H. - L.A. 1916real est.
  - Bailey, J.D. - L.A. 1908
  - Bailey, R.W. - L.A. 1908pres. Bailey Ornamental Iron Co.
  - Bailey Ornamental Iron Works - L.A. 1907s. R.W. Bailey, pres
  - Baird, J.G. - Hermon Cal. 1908princ. L.A. Seminary
  - Baker, Clara D. - n.d.,n.p. Children's Agent
  - Baker, Veorhis & Co - N.Y. 1921initialed L. K. Strcose, pres.
  - Ball, C.D. - Santa Ana, 1920
  - Ball Oil Burner Mfg Co. - L.A. 1918, n.d.s. M. Brussard, mgr.
  - Ballard, Charles D. - S.F. 1911
  - Baltz, J.H. - L.A. 1912dist. mgr. 65th Assb.
  - Balzer, George - Soldiers Home Cal. 1908
  - Bamberger, Julius - S.F. 1913
  - Bancroft, Nina Eldred - S.F. n.d. (ca. 1912)
  - Bancroft-Whitney Co. - S.F. 1920,21,publishers
  - Banning, Hancock - L.A. 19112nd v.p. Banning Co.
  - Bard, Thomas R. - Hueneme, Ventura Co. 1907, 09, 11, 12Repub. St. Cent. Com.
  - Bardill, John - L.A. 1910
  - Barham, W. W. - Yreka 1911tel. chairman. Siskiyou Co. Repub. Cent. Com.
  - Barkworth, Thomas E. - Jackson, Mich. 1905lawyer
  - Barnard, Charles N. - Whittier, Cal Dec.19?lawyer
  - Barnard, W.C. - S.F. (? Oakland) 1911Pab Serv. Cl. of Alameda Co.
  - Barnes, Celia L. 1912St. Pauls Paresh (Rev.
  - Barnet, Rose W. - L.A. 1911
  - Barnhill, William A. - L.A. 1915 1920, 21 -Lissnet's partner see also Comesp. Out
  - Barnum, Mary G. (Mrs. O. Sheparel) - Alhambra 1914, 15 n.d.Calif. St. Bd. of Ed. v.p.
  - Barr, M.E. - S.F. 1919tel.
  - Barrows, Chase Clifford. N.Y. 1908physician
  - Barrows, David P. - Berkeley 1915U.C. Dean of the Faculties
  - Barry, James D. - San Diego 1912atty
  - Barry, John F. - S.F. 1919 -?jr. partner of Lissner tel.
  - Bartels, B. W. - L.A. 1911
  - Bartlett, Alfred L. - Sacramento 1921tel.
  - Bartlett, Dana W. - L.A. 1905, 11, 12, 13, 15, 17supl. of Bethlehem, Hull House of L.A. Calif. Immigration Commission, L.A. Chantangua Assoc., chairman - L.A. Dept. Health But of Hsg
  - Bartlett, F.H. - Alameda 1917mayor
  - Bary, Helen V. - [1912]?So. Calif. Civic League
  - Batcheller, Charles L. - L.A. 1913, 19lawyer
  - Batturs, F.E. - L.A. 1911 -gen. pass. agt. So. Pac. Pacific System
  - Batty, George S. - L.A. 1911of Consolidated Realty Co.
  - Baumgartner, J.P. - Santa Ana 1910, 11, 12, 16, 20, 21ed. & mgr. Register Publishing Co, Inc. (Santa Ana Daily Register); pres. National Editorial Ass'n.
  - Bancroft, Philip - S.F. 1910-13, 17atty, sec. Roosevelt Progressive Repub. Lg. Calif., sec. Calif. Deleg Nat'l Republican Conv., Chicago 1912
  - Beach, S.G. - Placerville 1911, 12s. Oliver E. Bailey, sec.
  - Beach, W.W. - L.A. 1914
  - Beard, C.E. - Salt Lake, S.F., Montanu 1917, 1918
  - Beard, Charles A. - Wn., D.C. Nov. 1?
  - Beard, M.R. - Sacramento 1907mayor
  - Beatty, Willard W. - San Francisco 14, 1915Calif. Outlook
  - Beaver, H.S. (& C.E. Dresser) - L.A. 1906, 07
  - Beck, S. - L.A. 1918
  - Beck, Duplicator Co. - N.Y. 1907st. Ernest L. Beck, pres
  - Becker, Tracy Chatfield - L.A. 1911, 12, 16, 17, 18lawyer, dep Dist. Atty. L.A. Co.
  - Behr, William - L.A. 1919 -West Publishing Co.
  - Behrendt, Sam, Co. - L.A. 1908,s. H.T. Paddack off. mgr.
  - Behrendt - Levy Co., Inc. - L.A. 1916-18st. H. T. Paddack, gen. agts for Royal Indemnity
  - Behymer, L.E. - L.A. 1911, 12mgr. of distinguished artists
  - Belford, Samuel W. - Reno, Nev. 1919atty
  - Bell, Charles W. - Sacramento 1907, 08, 09, 11, 12, 13Calif. Senate & U.S. Hse. of Reps.
  - Bell, Wm. J. - S.F. 1911sec. Building Trades Republican Cl.
  - Bellows, E.C. - L.A. 1908
  - Belshaw, Charles M. - Autioch Cal. 1907, 08, 11state legislater 1909proposed to run for Gov.
  - Bemis, Edward W. - New Brighton, N.Y. 1911
  - Bender-Chaquette Co. - S.F. 1904, 06& F.B. Moss, sec.; C.A. Chaquette, pres.
  - Bender - Moss Co. - S.F. 1919s. H. S. Richardson
  - Benedict, H. Stanley - Sacramento 1911, 13, 15Calif. Assb. coms.: Corporations, Elections, Judiciary, Mun. Corps., Universities
  - Benjamin
  - Bennett, James S. - L.A. 1916
  - Bennett, John R. - N.Y. 1914lawyer
  - Bentley, C.H. - S.F. 1907, 11, 12, 19, 20pres. S.F. Chamber of Commerce, Calif. Fruit Canners Assoc.
  - Bergstrom, Edwin - L.A. 1920architect
  - Bernstein, Fred - Chicago 1921 -cousin of Lewinsohn, master in Chancery, Superior Cook Cty.
  - Berry, F.P. - L.A. 1911
  - Bertram, G.H. - see Stanislans Co Repub. Cent. Com.
  - Bertsche, C.P. -S.F. 1917
  - Beveridge, Albert J. - Indianapolis, Ind. 1910, 12, 13, 18, 19, 20, 21U.S. Senator from Indiana, author of biography (? John) Marshall
  - Beasly, W. A. - San Jose 15, 1917, 18, 19, 20, 21judge supercat of S.A. Roosevelt Repub
  - Beatty John A. - Santa Ana 1907, 08, 10, 11, 12by goods, finance com.
  - Biby, John E - L.A. 1912atty
  - Bichowsky, E.C. - Pomona, 1908pres. bd. dir. Pomona Valley Hospital Assoc. pres. Pomona Implement Co.
  - Bidwell, George F. - L.A. 1917chairman City Club Com. on Pub. Util.
  - Bill, John T. & Co. - L.A. 1916s. S.T. Bill
  - Bine, René - S.F. 16, 1917physician
  - Binkard, Robert S. - N.Y. 19131 tel. sec. City Club of New York
  - Birdsall, E.S. - E. Auburn, Cal. 1913, 15Calif Senate chairman. Com. on Roads & Highways
  - Birkel, George S. - L.A. 1916
  - Birkel, Geo S., Co. - L.A. 1913
  - Bishoff, Henry S. - San Diegg - 1920atty
  - Bishop, Richard M. - L.A. 1915real est.
  - Bishop, Sam - L.A. 1917
  - Bishop & Co. - L.A. 1911
  - Bixby, Fred H. - Long Beach, Cal. 1912
  - Benjamin, Raymond - S.F. 16 1918-21chf dep. atty gen. (Calif 1918)chairman. Repub. State (Calif.) Central Com. chairman exec. com.
  - Blair, Isidot D. - L.A. 1913lawget
  - Blaney, Charles D. - Saratoga, Cal. 1915, 16, 17real est. pers. (Saratoga)
  - Blaney, Isabella W. - (Mrs. C.D.) - Chicago 1912, 13pers. Natl Committeeman Progressive Progressive Nat'l Com.
  - Bonfield, Anne - Emporia, Kas. 1921see. to W.A. White
  - Lankenhorn David Co - Pasadena 1912s. Colin Stewart, Colin Steward, Jr.
  - Blight, Reynold E. - L.A. 1910-13, 15, 17mgr. Lester Herrick & Herrick C.P.A.
  - Bliven, Bruce Orms by - L.A. 1915, 16advertising, U.C.L.A. prof. journalism
  - Block, Israel - Oakland 1911, 13, 15, 16?uncle of Mrs. Lissner
  - Bloom, Eve -?. N. Y. n.d.cousin
  - Bloomfield, Meyer - Boston 1915 n.d.dir. Vocation Bureau
  - Blackmar, Charles A. - L.A. 1911 -Dept. of Oil Inspection L.A. inspector
  - Blackstock, Charles F. - Oxnard, Cal. 1912, 16, [18]atty
  - Blalock, Ugene U. - 1920
  - Blanchard, F.W. - L.A. 1911pres. Municipal Art Commission
  - B'nal B'rith, Independent Order Of - L.A. 1921Lodge 487 Anti-Defamation Com. s. M. Silverberg pres. Rabbi Edgar F. Magnin
  - Bohan, E.R. - L.A. 1921League for World Freedom
  - Boke, George H. - S.F. 1909, 12Citizens' League of Justice, U.C. Dept of Jurisprudence
  - Bolton, Bonaparte
  - Booth, W. H. - L.A. 1913, 16v.p. Security Trust & Savings Bank Senatorial 1916
  - Boothby
  - Borglum, Elizabeth Venice 1919
  - Borree
  - Boston City Club - Boston, Mass. 1908s. William S. Youngmen, see.; Addison L. Winship, civic sec.
  - Bosshard, R.E. - Alameda 1917City Clerk
  - Bourne, Jonathan Jr. - Wn. D.C. 1911U.S. Senator (Oregon)
  - Boynton, Albert E. - Oroville 1910-13, 19, 20, 21atty, pres. pro-tem Calif. Senate, St. Bd. of Presen Directors of Calif., sec. Johnson for Pres. Nat'l Cmpgn Com. 1920
  - Boynton, Mary L. (Mrs. H. R.) L.A. - 1911, 12, 13
  - Beethby, B. O. - Sacramento 16 1919chief clerk Calif. Senate
  - Borree, J.J. - Sacramento 1917brig. gen. Cal. Nat'l Cd., Adjutant Gen.
  - Bolton Printing Co., Inc. - L.A. 1916s. Mrs. William paris Bolton
  - Burr, B.A. Wn. D.C. 1919see. to U.S. Rep. (Calif.) Julius Kahn
  - Bradley, Christopher M. - S.F. 16 1917, 18, 19, 20 & n.d.atty Indus. Acc. Comn. Counsel
  - Braun, F.W. - L.A. 1912,present gen'l mgr. F.W.Braun Co., treas. Munic. Conf. of 1913
  - Braun, F.W. Co. - L.A. 1907s. L.N. Brunswig 1st v.p.
  - Breed, Arthur H. - Oakland 1912, 15, 17, 18pres. Breed & Bancroft real est. - Calif. Senate - chairman. Co. Gov't. Com., Pres. Pro Tem
  - Brown, Walter F. - N.Y. 1913Progressive Nat'l Com. chairman Organ. Com., (1)
  - Brown, William E.- Sacramento 1913, 15, 17Calif. Senate chairman Prisons & Reformatories Com.
  - Brundige, H.W. - L.A. 11 1912L.A.Express
  - Brunswig, L.N. - L.A. 1911, 15, 16, 17Brunswig Drug Co., v.p. F.W.Braun Co.
  - Bryant, Carrie Parsons - L.A. 11 1912, 13pres. Womens Progressive Lg. of Calif. exec. bd